# EMILY CENTKO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## ABOUT

With an educational background in English, language, and writing, upon moving to Nashville, I began working in customer experience for e-commerce and tech-based companies. I developed an interest in the user experience surrounding technology—it allowed me to bolster my problem-solving and communication skills, and eventually, led me to coding. I've been on the search for a career I love, and I felt right at home in software development.

## **PROJECTS**

## **WATCHLIST**

#### FRONT-END CAPSTONE

I developed a single-page application that enables a user to create multiple movie "playlists." This app uses user-specific data, allowing a user to search and add favorite movies to organize into their own curated watchlists based on genre, director, or theme (or however you like) utilizing full CRUD functionality. I built it using React, pulled movie data using a third-party API (TMDb), and styled it with Material UI and CSS.

github.com/emilycentko/watchlist

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- HTML5, CSS3, Material UI
- JavaScript, React.js
- Python, Django

## **EDUCATION**

## NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full-Stack Software Development 2021

## **UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE**

Bachelor's of Arts in English 2013

## **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2021 - Present

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development using HTML, CSS, Python & Django

- Built single-page applications using JavaScript and React to create dynamic user experiences
- Experienced working in teams, learning to collaborate and communicate effectively to deliver working solutions
- Learned the importance of planning fundamentals using entity relationship diagrams, building wireframes, and fostering a growth mindset
- Object-oriented programming using third-party APIs and local databases.

## **CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE**

## Warby Parker

Customer Experience Advisor | 2017 - Present

 Helped coordinate and train a team of international shipping experts, tracking shipping issues, monitoring trends, and improving internal processes

Content Optimization & Content Creation Projects | 2017 - 2019

- Reviewed and audited over 200 email, chat, and SMS text expansions for responses to frequently asked questions to help increase efficiencies
- Worked cross-functionally with other teams to create new product trainings for all customer-facing teams in the company Social Media Team | 2017 - 2019
- Responded to comments, posts, and direct messages across Warby Parker's Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook pages to resolve customer questions and issues

#### **Eventbrite**

Customer Experience Advisor | 2016 - 2017

- Problem-solved technical support for event organizers via email and phone on a technical event platform.
- Requirements gathering to guide users in learning the best ways to set up and manage events
- Used creative issue resolution skills to diagnose and troubleshoot user issues